

11 Gun Place, 86 Wapping Lane E1W 2RX London

T +44 7557 146694 E carlos@butler.cc LI butler.cc/linkedin

Profile

Designer, technologist, and innovator for social payments and platforms.

I have worked in numerous sectors with infrastructures and projects that range from internal, highly specific low latency systems to large, consumer facing services on both desktop and mobile. This includes server-side development and API's, client AJAX frameworks and interfaces, and hybrid mobile applications.

I work with businesses by ensuring the products being developed are exactly fit for purpose and always strive for the cleanest, simplest and most logical solution to even the most complex of software or operational tasks.

Experience

Co-founder and CTO, GenRent Energy – May 2016 - May 2017

With a lot of the business operations outsourced, I suggested, and then agreed by the board, to bring in all operations in house. I was responsible for an entire overhaul of the internal and external operational systems alongside a new consumer facing dashboard, pricing and signup system, completely new consumer payment system, bill generation and invoicing, and internal automated administrative operations and messaging system using a combination of SMS, dashboard notifications and email.

I was tasked with designing and presenting the new system and it's sub-projects to the board of directors, where the timelines were then decided and agreed on. Due to very tight budgets I was the only developer on the project, and it had to be released in steps to ensure operations could start quickly. The first customer signup and payment authorization was taken just 4 weeks after the project commenced.

During this process I was responsible for every single aspect, from system architecture and database design, maintainable build and release processes, to code design and development, front-end user interface design and external payment API's.

Needless to say, this was a huge achievement with all the above being completed in under 3 months, without taking in to account daily co-founder and director tasks. However, having ensured I receive constant feedback and plenty of UAT the end result was a great success, with the operational staff commending the ease of use to manage customers, and customers alike having a great experience setting up their energy accounts, direct debits and viewing all their information on the reactive-front end website.

Experience

Co-founder and CTO, BillHub – January 2014 - May 2017

Managed concept-to-market consumer facing products with numerous iterations of various billing systems (direct debit, over the phone and debit/credit card). This included infrastructure design, code, implementation and continuous release cycles.

The projects were broken down and assigned specific budgets to hire contractors and the timelines were agreed by the board of directors, all of which I was responsible for.

One of the last projects worked on was a native mobile payments app that allowed very easy P2P payments, and group collection of payments for events. The app was successfully launched just 4 weeks after initial project discussion and was used by a couple of hundred users before it was stopped due to cost concerns.

I was responsible for every single aspect of all technology, from server infrastructure, security and code release to operational cloud communication and HR systems. All server side systems and API's were developed in Rails.

KDB Developer and DevOps Consultant, UBS Investment Bank – May 2013 - April 2014 Part of a small, niche team on the foreign exchange trading floor responsible for developing internal tools used by algorithmic traders, managing terabytes of weekly currency data and having quick release cycles for fast changing business requirements.

Alongside tools, introducing operational changes such as moving to Git, continuous integration, worldwide privately owned server configuration using Puppet and automated testing methods.

Developer and Mobile App Consultant, Accenture - 2010-2011

Education

Loughborough University – Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence 2:1 - 2008-2012

Skills

- Product and software, design and development. User flow and experience.
- · Development management.
- Project management, managing contractor work and developing on the same projects.
- Partnership and deal-making.
- Intermediary skills, having acted on numerous difficult disagreements between fellow directors ensuring resolutions were agreed in a fair, logical and least-stressful manner.

Technologies

- Ruby on Rails 4 and 5, MySQL, with multi-server environments and relevant integration tools
- AngularJS, various other JS frameworks and Bootstrap CSS framework
- Cordova based framework for hybrid mobile application development
- Cloud based infrastructure and external off-site backup solutions

Achievements

- Starting a business from scratch with no seed investment and growing it to 8 full time, well paid employees in two years.
- Being invited to and joining British Mensa UK.
- Being one of the youngest Institute of Advanced Motorists advanced riders and teachers, and winning the 2017 Southern Young Biker of the Year.